<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flesh eating bacteria.</title>
    <link>https://blog.setefaces.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Flesh eating bacteria.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Leandro Santiago - 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 10:26:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.setefaces.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are You Hiding?</title>
      <link>https://blog.setefaces.org/post/what-are-you-hiding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 10:26:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.setefaces.org/post/what-are-you-hiding/</guid>
      <description>The C++ visibility model is broken by design. By visibility model I mean using the keywords private, public and protected to manage how objects relate to each other.
I will explain exactly how such model is broken and propose a workaround to it. I admit I am not the first one to realize that, as I have been writting C++ for just a decade, whereas there are more skilled programmers than me or with way more experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testable Singletons in C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://blog.setefaces.org/post/testable-singletons-in-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 20:50:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.setefaces.org/post/testable-singletons-in-cpp/</guid>
      <description>TL-DR: make the getInstance() method of a Singleton return an abstract type and allow it to be overriden at link-time.
Disclaimer: the technique here explained is maybe as old as C++. I don&amp;rsquo;t claim to be the author of the idea. I just wish I had learned it 10 years ago.
So you hate, or at least dislike, the Singleton pattern, right?
I am not its fan and can&amp;rsquo;t recall the last time I created one, but we must accept the fact that they exist in the wild, specially in legacy codebases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://blog.setefaces.org/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 20:07:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.setefaces.org/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Well, after many years (really) I decided, again, to make a blog. As usual, it will be mostly about software development and other things that happen between my ears.
Stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>